Chapter 2: Upon Returning

Approximately two weeks had passed since his departure from the spirit folk village.

Rio stepped onto Strahl soil for the first time in several years; his current location was the trade city of Amande, located in the western region of the Kingdom of Galarc. As it was a part of Duke Cretia’s territory, Rio had once stopped in this city on his way out of the Strahl region.

However, Amande had developed greatly since then, making it quite different compared to how it had been several years ago; it was actually still under development even now. From what Rio could see as he approached through the air, deforestation was occurring, which clearly secured more area for the city.

I guess I’ll go down and gather some information first.

Rio wasn’t about to brazenly land in the middle of the city, so he descended into the vast forest near Amande instead. Location-wise, Amande was close both to the Kingdom of Beltrum to the west and the Kingdom of Centostella near the south, so it was a good spot to gather foreign information.

After locating a deserted road, he exited the forest to see Amande within view and felt its growth even more strongly. It was a scenery he would have seen several years ago, but it was completely unfamiliar to him now; although with the size of the city expanding, it was only natural that the outer areas would grow larger, too. While he was flying, Rio had seen the sturdy castle walls that surrounded the inner city, but the outer city was only enclosed by wooden fencing.

He entered the city from the east road. There are so many buildings I don’t recognize. Or maybe I just don’t remember them?

Rio gazed at the city landscape with curiosity. He had only stayed in Amande for a single day all those years ago, so his memories of the city weren’t that clear to begin with. However, the overflowing energy within the city hadn’t changed at all. No — it was possible it was bustling even more now than it had been before, with several stalls set up along the main street, their vendors calling for customers’ attention.

As Rio walked along the road and fondly reminisced, he finally spotted a certain building in his view. It was the inn he had previously stayed at for one night.

This was where I stayed last time. What was the name of the girl in the inn again? Well, I’m sure she doesn’t remember me, either.

Rio smiled bitterly, remembering how a couple of drunks had bothered him and caused a scene. Unfortunately, he had no business with the inn right now, so he passed on by.

Suddenly, six pillars of blinding light shot up in every direction visible from Amande. The pillars of light seemed to be a phenomenon of sorcery or spirit arts, as they were spreading waves of ode and mana all throughout Strahl, even causing the air to tremble. As a result, not only did Rio notice the light pillars immediately with his excellent ode and mana detection abilities as a spirit arts user, but the residents of Amande did, too.

“Look at that!”

“There’s one there too!”

“They’re all different colors.”

“W-Wow, what is it?”

The city was instantly in an uproar; everyone was looking in every direction, gazing at the red, blue, white, green, brown, and yellow pillars.

Rio was staring at the pillars, too, when —

“?!”

Ba-dump. He felt something like an intense beat within his heart, making him open his eyes widely. He placed a hand against his chest reflexively, and felt a pleasantly warm heat rising within him.

Haruto.

...Haru... ...-er.

...-ve... them.

The strangely familiar voice of a girl echoed in the back of Rio’s head.

“...Who is that?”

Rio opened his mouth in amazement. He couldn’t make out what she had said, but it was definitely the voice of a girl. But, as far as he could see around him, the owner of the voice didn’t appear to be nearby.

Sharpen... your senses.

Go... southeast.

...will be... waiting... there...

The girl’s voice echoed again, and in that next moment, Rio felt his senses sharpen dramatically.

“This...”

Rio knew this sensation — he had experienced it once before. He had felt it when he had regained his memories of Amakawa Haruto.

Rio had met Flora as a dirty orphan in a shabby shack, when he was suddenly attacked by an unknown man. He had heard the mysterious voice of a girl back then, too; it sharpened his senses and helped him overcome the crisis at hand.

“...You want me to head southeast?” Rio asked hesitantly, but there was no response. The light pillars had disappeared at some point too.

He had no idea if the voice he heard was real or not, and it was possible that he had just misheard something. However, Rio had one possible explanation in mind.

Is it the voice of the spirit inside me? Rio thought. Perhaps the pulsing in his chest just before he heard the voice was caused by the spirit girl residing within him.

The voice had told him to go southeast, because there was someone waiting there. Could that someone be the owner of the voice? If so, it couldn’t possibly be the spirit within Rio.

...I don’t know. Rio shook his head uneasily. Just thinking about it wouldn’t give him any answers. But the truth was, the directions came from a girl who had saved him once before.

“...I’ll go and take a look.”

Rio decided to head southeast for now; he turned on his heel and weaved his way through the chaotic crowds, walking back the way he came to leave the city once more.

Several minutes after that, he entered the forest neighboring the city of Amande, and used his spirit arts to fly up into the air, heading southeast.

◇◇◇

Obeying the order of the voice that echoed in his head, Rio proceeded southeast. However, after nearly an hour of flying at a steady speed and surveying his surroundings, he couldn’t find any particular oddities.

The direction to head southeast had been pretty vague to begin with, and he didn’t know how far southeast he needed to move. While he had been spurred into action by the situation at hand and the strange sensation in his chest, he had regained his senses by now.

Guess I’ll turn back.

Just as he thought that, with his senses that had been strangely sharpened since the events earlier, Rio noticed the ode and mana was heavily disrupted in a corner of the grasslands before him.

“...What’s that? The distortion is almost like the aftermath of time-space sorcery...”

Rio gulped and widened his eyes. Reflected within them was the light of significantly stagnant ode in the air; it was similar to the phenomenon characteristic of the aftermath of using time-space sorcery.

This amount of residual essence is unprecedented. Judging by the way it’s disrupted, not much time has passed yet... Did someone use teleportation sorcery? Rio speculated, taking into consideration the situation left before him. However, from what he could see in the air, there was no sign of anyone at the scene nor in the surrounding plains.

There don’t seem to be any spell formulas set up. In that case, the teleport sorcery was either to a random destination, or the destination was set to here... At any rate, not even the basics of time-space sorcery could be performed with the standard of sorcery in Strahl. The only possibility would be an ancient artifact. Guess I’ll go down and have a look first, Rio speculated, then decided to descend to the spot for now.

As soon as he stepped down onto the grassland, a cold wind noisily brushed against his skin and shook the endless expanse of grass. Rio carefully dragged his gaze over the surroundings, searching for any remaining traces.

This place is a fair distance from the road, and the perfect spot to hide away and do something, but these... are footsteps... Enhanced with spirit arts, Rio’s vision discovered the faint footsteps amongst trampled grass.

There were three sets of footprints. Each set headed directly south, right in the direction of Centostella, the kingdom located furthest to the southeast of the Strahl region.

There’s no mistaking the fact they arrived by teleportation sorcery. Could these be the people that voice was talking about before? I don’t think it could be a coincidence.

It seemed he would need to investigate further. With a small sigh, Rio flew up into the air and followed the footsteps with his spirit arts.

“Good morning, Aki,” Rio greeted with a strained smile.

“G-Good morning,” Aki managed to reply hesitantly. She seemed to maintain her calm better than Masato did.

“I’d like to introduce her to the two of you, but shall we sit down first?”

Rio decided to explain the situation to Aki and Masato right away.

◇◇◇

Rio gave a simple explanation of what happened to Aki and Masato and introduced them to the spirit girl.

“...So that’s how it is. Masato, were you listening?” Rio asked with a droll smile. Masato had been distracted throughout the entirety of Rio’s explanation, captivated by the girl in a fluster.

“Y-Yeah. I was. She’s the spirit lady Haruto’s contracted with, right?” Masato glanced at the spirit’s face before nodding, his voice oddly high-pitched.

“Well, yes...” Rio wondered with a wry smile and a tilt of his head as to whether or not Masato would be able to live together with her.

Aki looked at Masato from where she sat beside him. “Don’t let him bother you. He always falls in love at first sight with cute and pretty girls older than him. It seems like he’s suffering from his affliction more severely this time around, but he’ll eventually get used to it, so just cut him some slack for now,” she explained to Rio with an exasperated face.

“Ahaha.”

“Wha— T-That’s not true!” Masato blushed furiously with embarrassment.

Aki shook her head without hesitation. “Liar. You were so nervous the first time you met Miharu, too. Your brother was quite an amusing sight to see, but you were even worse than him.”

“Wahwahwah!” Masato started yelling as though to drown out her voice.

“What are you two yelling about this early in the morning? Come on, breakfast is ready.”

Miharu appeared from the kitchen; she was carrying the completed breakfast dishes from the kitchen counter toward the dining room table.

“Sorry, Miharu. I left you to deal with breakfast alone... Let me help you carry it,” Rio said apologetically, stepping forward to help set the table.

“It’s fine. I can at least handle the housework.” Miharu shook her head with a smile.

“...Thank you very much. It looks delicious.” Rio smiled at the dishes lined on the table; she had prepared a well-balanced Japanese meal.

“I hope the taste is to your liking... Let’s all eat now. Umm, I made enough for the spirit girl, too, but will you be able to eat the food?” Miharu asked, looking at the spirit. While she looked exactly like a human, it was hard to imagine spirits eating meals like everyone else.

The girl slowly drew closer and nodded. “Yeah. I can eat.”

“Thank goodness. Let’s eat together, then. Here.” Miharu took the girl by the hand and led her to the dining table.

Rio watched the two of them with a smile. They had completely different hair colors, yet they looked like sisters for some reason, Miharu being the older one, most likely.

After that, the five of them sat in their seats and began to eat their breakfast.

“It’s kind of inconvenient not being able to call her by a name, though. Have you considered what you’re going to do about that?” Miharu asked Rio partway through the meal as she looked at the spirit girl.

“Actually, she’s requested for me to give her a name, but I’m stuck on ideas for good names. Do you have any suggestions, Miharu?” Rio asked her with a dry smile.

Miharu started to think with a contemplative look on her face, but couldn’t come up with anything good on the spot. “Hmm. When you put it that way... it’s kind of difficult. What kind of name would you like?” she asked, turning to the girl in question.

“As long as it’s a name Haruto picks, anything.”

The girl’s answer made Miharu smile faintly. “Ahaha. You sure are loved, Haruto.”

“Good for you, Haruto,” Masato muttered under his breath.

“Do you have anything more specific than that? Maybe if there’s something you like, you could go in that direction for ideas,” Aki suggested to the spirit girl, ignoring Masato.

“The things that Haruto loves and treasures,” the spirit girl answered simply.

“Ahaha, I see. If that’s the case, then you should just use Haruto’s name as a base for your own,” Aki said with a bitter smile.

...The things that I love or treasure? Rio thought to himself, glancing at Miharu.

“...?” Noticing she was being looked at, Miharu cocked her head in question.

The first thing that came to mind was Miharu... Just how stubborn am I? With a bitter smile, Rio guiltily averted his gaze.

However, thanks to that, one name came to mind.

“How about... Aishia?”

In the ancient spirit folk tongue, “Aishia” was a word that meant “warm spring” or “beautiful spring.” It may have been a bit too simplistic, but the girl’s hair was the gentle peach color of cherry blossoms, so she gave off a rather strong impression of spring.

However, now that he had said it out loud, he realized “beautiful spring” was the exact same meaning as Miharu’s name. He felt rather embarrassed by it.

“Aishia. I want that one,” the spirit girl said resolutely.

“...Umm, we could keep thinking with everyone and come up with a few options first,” Rio offered as he panicked on the inside.

“Nope. Aishia’s good.” Aishia shook her head bluntly.

She hadn’t shown many emotions or expressions since waking up, but the firm resolution that had been revealed just now made Rio widen his eyes. “Well, if you’re happy with that, then I guess that’s it?” he said, giving in with a wry smile.

“Aishia... That sounds like a pretty name,” Miharu said, murmuring the name as though testing it. “Does it have a meaning?” she asked Rio.

“Umm. It means ‘warm spring,’” he replied, feeling somewhat uncomfortable. He kept the other meaning to himself.

“...I see. You took the ‘haru’ from Haruto, right? The one that means ‘spring,’ as in the season.” Convinced, Miharu guessed at the explanation of the meaning.

“...Yes, that’s right.” Rio averted his gaze from Miharu and looked at Aishia. The girl in question should have known the meaning behind the name, but who knew how she felt about it.

“Miharu, Aki, Masato. It’s nice to meet you.” Aishia bowed her head at the three of them. Since her name had now been officially decided, she greeted them once more.

“Yeah, it’s nice to meet you. Ai-chan... Can I call you that?” Miharu asked happily.

“Yup, that’s fine.” Aishia nodded nonchalantly, but the hints of a smile could be seen on her mouth. Aki and Masato spoke up to Aishia, too.

Rio watched the four of them with a smile on his face, but there was a lot he needed to think about regarding the future.

I don’t really want to cause them any trouble, but if I can get permission, it might be better to consider bringing Aishia and everyone to the spirit folk village. I would need to head there myself first to get permission from them, but I should at least wait until the others can speak the language in broken sentences... Rio thought in the corner of his mind.

The spirit folk might know something, whether it be about Aishia or Miharu and the others. It would have taken Rio a month or so to make the return trip there alone, but with the teleport crystal he received from Ursula, he could shorten half of the trip. Even with the crystal it was still quite a trip, but it was an option worth considering.

Well, first things first: the shopping for today. There might be some things that are difficult to buy with me around, so I’ll bring Aishia along as an interpreter. I’ll ask her about it later.

As Rio looked at Aishia, he turned his thoughts toward the day’s shopping trip.

“Y-Yes! The Sacred Stone I carry in my custody suddenly began to glow, just before it let out a huge pillar of light. According to the prophecy of the Six Wise Gods, the hero will appear by the Sacred Stone one-thousand years after the Holy Era begins.” Flora explained in a rather rushed way as best she could.

Hiroaki organized his thoughts. “...Ah, wait, hold on a sec. Let’s calm down first, princess. Putting aside the meanings of all those words for now, what you’re saying is that I appeared by the Sacred Stone you carry. That’s why I’m the hero?”

“Y-Yes. That’s why.” Flora nodded.

“I see. Well, this is a fairly cliché situation if I’ve ever seen one. And you can understand Japanese, for some reason. I suppose being on Easy Mode isn’t that bad...” Hiroaki murmured to himself.

“U-Umm.” Flora carefully watched Hiroaki’s face. “May I please ask for your name, great hero?” she inquired.

“...I’m Sakata Hiroaki.” Hiroaki ruffled his hair in a pompous gesture. “Just to clear it up now, Sakata is my family name and Hiroaki is my first name. I’d like to ask you something too. Where am I?”

“This is Marquess Rodan’s territory in the northeast of Beltrum. The consulate of the capital of Rodania.”

“Have you ever heard of these country names: Japan, America, England, France, Germany, or China?”

“Erm, I have not.” Flora shook her head apologetically.

“I see...” Hiroaki sighed a small sigh.

I’ve got an idea of the general picture now, at least... This is what you would call your typical cliché fantasy trip. Judging from the princess’s attitude, there’s no mistaking that the hero is of a similar status to royalty. If so, whether I’m actually the hero or not, would it be better to pretend I’m the hero anyway? While it’d be annoying to be treated as their go-to guy to solve all their problems, I don’t want them to look down on me, and I need more information. If I’m going to negotiate with them, I need to stand above them.

At the very least, Flora was a fair maiden, and it wasn’t bad to be respected as a hero. And so, he braced himself to be able to carry himself with skill and tact.

“So, who’s your friend there?” Hiroaki addressed the middle-aged man standing next to Flora. He appeared to be of a rather high-ranking status.

“Pardon my rudeness. I am the duke, Gustav Huguenot. Due to certain circumstances, I am currently serving as Her Highness Princess Flora’s guardian. Pleased to make your acquaintance.”

Duke Huguenot pasted a sociable smile on his face and greeted him respectfully. However, his eyes showed no trace of weakness as he carefully observed Hiroaki.

“Got it. For now, I’d like to get a better understanding of the situation. I’m sure you would agree, right? Don’t you think we owe each other some explanations?”

Duke Huguenot nodded agreeably. “Indeed, that is true. Allow me to show you to a place where we can discuss this while seated.”

“Great. Thanks.” Hiroaki headed toward the mansion with Flora and her entourage.

◇◇◇

Several minutes later, Hiroaki was lowering himself into a sofa across from Flora and her group.

“This is George Rodan, the lord of this territory,” Duke Huguenot said.

“An honor to meet you, hero. I am most delighted to welcome the hero of legend into my humble residence.” The middle-aged Marquess Rodan bowed his head at Hiroaki with reverence.

“Yeah, nice to meet you. Are you going to tell me the names of those knights over there, too? They seem pretty young... Even younger than me, and I’m nineteen.” Hiroaki curiously looked at the two knights standing behind Flora.

“They’re our sons. As you can see, they’re in their mid-teens, and have a long way to go. I allowed their presence here, hoping it would be a good lesson for them. Does this displease you?”

“I see... The sons of Huguenot and Rodan. I don’t mind, but... I’d like them to remove their weapons, at least,” Hiroaki warily requested while leaving his own longsword by his side. The two young knights stiffened by a fraction.

“Pardon our rudeness. You two — disarm yourselves,” Duke Huguenot ordered them with a smile.

“Yes, sir.” The two boys nodded uncomfortably, taking their scabbards from their waists.

“I shall take care of those.” A girl in noble clothing approached from the corner of the room and retrieved the two swords.

“Thank you.” The boys greeted the girl with a small bow.

“This is a good opportunity. The three of you, introduce yourselves to the hero,” Duke Huguenot urged.

“...Nice to meet you, hero. I am Stewart Huguenot.”

“...I’m Alphonse Rodan. It’s a pleasure to meet you.” The two boys introduced themselves to Hiroaki first in stiff voices, watching him with faintly dubious eyes.

“It is an honor to meet you. My name is Roanna Fontaine. Pleased to make your acquaintance.” The noble girl smiled elegantly as she introduced herself.

Hiroaki widened his eyes, captivated by Roanna’s smile. “Yeah... Nice to meet you. Sorry, but you were standing in a corner, so I didn’t notice you. I cannot allow a lady to remain standing while I sit, though... Won’t you take a seat?”

Roanna shook her head with a troubled expression. “No, I’m...”

“If the hero says to sit down, then take a seat, Roanna,” Duke Huguenot insisted.

“...Thank you very much for your consideration, hero. Then, if you would excuse me.” Roanna lifted her skirt and curtsied, then entrusted Stewart and Alphonse’s swords in her hands to a servant and sat down on the sofa. Hiroaki watched her with a smirk at his lips.

“Now, may we proceed to the main point of our discussion, hero?” Duke Huguenot asked. Hiroaki nodded coolly. “There’s something I’d like to ask first.”

“What might it be? If it’s something we can answer, we shall answer to the best of our ability...”

“What summoned me was that Sacred Stone thing held by Princess Flora, right?” Hiroaki asked, looking at the princess.

“Y-Yes. That’s right!” Flora agreed almost nervously.

“The fact I’ve been summoned means that — naturally — I can go back too, right?”

“Huh? Go back? Umm, that’s...” Hiroaki’s question must have been unexpected, as Flora was rendered speechless. Her reaction was enough to tip off the sensitive hero.

“Oi oi, don’t tell me you summoned me here with no way for me to get back.”

“No, it’s just... Umm... I don’t know...”

“If you don’t know, then doesn’t that make this an abduction? Taking someone away against their will is considered a crime in this world, too, is it not?” Hiroaki pushed without giving Flora time to respond.

“I-I’m sorry. I don’t know the circumstances either, so we’re actually a little troubled by it all...” With her naturally gentle disposition, Flora could do nothing but apologize in return; her side of it had no idea what was going on, either. The Sacred Stone had summoned Hiroaki by itself, so calling it an abduction was a rather extreme way of misunderstanding the situation.

“Ah, it’s not like I’m trying to be mean. It’s just that I’m the one in a bind because of this, you know?” Even Hiroaki seemed to feel ashamed of persecuting a pretty girl like Flora, as he inclined his head guiltily.

“Hero, isn’t your attitude toward Her Highness rather rude? Is this the proper manner of a hero?” Stewart objected with furrowed brows.

“Stewart!” Duke Huguenot called in a stern voice.

“Guh... My deepest apologies,” Stewart said with a vexed expression.

Duke Huguenot bowed his head deeply at Hiroaki. “Please pardon my son’s rudeness, hero.”

“Ah, don’t get the wrong idea. I’m not trying to pick a fight or anything. It’s just that I had a life in my original world, too. One that was unfairly taken away from me. I just wanted to make that clear. If you all participated in my abduction, then we should approach this in a logical manner. Even if you suddenly tell me that I’m the hero, there’s not much I can do about it.” Hiroaki shook his head.

“That applies to us, too... And the abduction is a misunderstanding. It looks like there is a need to lay all our cards on the table and discuss things properly. We vow to tell you everything we know at this point in time, hero. Will you lend us an ear?” Duke Huguenot asked with a slightly perplexed look.

“Yeah, that’d be great. Even if you talk about Six Wise Gods and Sacred Stones and heroes, it doesn’t really make sense to me,” Hiroaki said with a relaxed smile.

After that, Duke Huguenot explained various facts to Hiroaki, including their request for the hero’s cooperation.

At that very same moment, Miharu and the others were wandering about the grasslands.

Afterword

Hello, everyone — this is Yuri Kitayama. Thank you very much for picking up Seirei Gensouki, Volume 4: Eternal You.

So, the fourth volume of the Seirei Gensouki novel has finally gone on sale. Two years ago, I would have never imagined myself having a career writing books, and now I’ve already released four volumes. You really don’t know what’ll happen to you in life.

That being said, I haven’t quite gotten used to the idea of myself as an author, or maybe my identity as an author is still too weak, and I haven’t quite gotten used to calling myself Yuri Kitayama.

For example, when someone suddenly calls me Kitayama out of the blue, I sometimes think: “Who’s that?” in confusion... In another instance, someone from the editing department called me on the phone and I nearly answered with my real name; my nerves made my head completely blank and unable to recall my own series title, leaving me mumbling over my words. Embarrassing. (laughs)

But, well, as I’m living the busy author life doing this and that, I’m returning to my early days of writing for fun and enjoying it.

However, I seem to have trouble switching from my usual leisurely pace, so it takes me a while to get into the zone and my writing time is rather unstable. This is something I only noticed recently (I’m slow!).

Well, I’m also the type to get lost in concentration once I get in the zone, so I’ve been training myself to focus more consistently lately. Thanks to those efforts, the process of writing volume 4 felt like a much smoother experience.

Furthermore, with this volume, we finally get a glimpse of the heroine that appeared in volume 1 once more, so I was keen to finally start the real story from here onward. The subtitle “Eternal You” has a few different meanings, which will be revealed as the story continues. For now, I’d appreciate it if everyone took in the meaning in their own way after reading what happened in this volume.

I touched upon how the light novel version will have similarities to the web novel version — while also being an independent series on its own — in the afterword of the first volume. However, I believe the readers of both novels will find that the independence of this series has strengthened now with the release of volume four. The reason for this is that volume one through three have stuck to the storyline of the web novel fairly faithfully, but volume four has branched off from the web novel in order to include new adventurous developments and possibilities.

From here on out, there is a great chance volume five and beyond will get into parts of the story not covered in the web novel (some of which have been touched upon already), so readers who read the light novel alongside the web novel can look forward to those changes.

And, for readers who choose to only read the light novel and not the web novel, you may be able to enjoy this work more by comparing the differences to the web novel at a point further along in the light novel’s storyline (of course, the timing to read the web novel is the reader’s choice, and you are free to choose not to read the web novel at all).

With this, I have gone through great pains here and there with the light novel and web novel to make many ways of enjoying the series, but I’m sure the biggest thing on the readers’ minds is Professor Celia, who hasn’t appeared since volume one.

Professor Celia finally appeared at the very end of this volume, but I’ve had many readers tell me “Give us more Celia, quickly!” ever since volume one went on sale.

And so, to the 300,000 Professor Celia fans around the nation (this is an arbitrary number based on my own personal wishes [laughs]), thank you for waiting!

With volume five, it’ll finally be Professor Celia’s turn! I’ve actually had the subtitle of volume five decided ever since volume three went on sale, with all the events I wanted to write having been decided, so please look forward to what happens in volume five!

But, I also have good news for those who say: “I can’t wait until volume five!”

At the same time as the sale of this volume, the completely free novel site “Yomeru! HJ Bunko,” officially operated by HJ Bunko, will post side stories from the perspective of Professor Celia in the light novel Seirei Gensouki (timeline-wise, the stories take place after the epilogue of volume one).

Furthermore, I’ve also been interviewed by Light Novel News Online with the release of this volume, and thanks to them, I’ll be hosting a signing event. Please check online for further details regarding those.

Finally, to everyone who has supported Seirei Gensouki, I’d like to use this space to thank you all. I am only here as an author thanks to all the wonderful support that everyone has given me. I hope we can continue our relationship for a long time.

Thank you very much.

30 April 2016 Yuuri Kitayama